[
  { "front": "die Mutter", "back": "mother" },
  { "front": "der Vater", "back": "father" },
  { "front": "die Eltern", "back": "parents" },
  { "front": "der Sohn", "back": "son" },
  { "front": "die Tochter", "back": "daughter" },
  { "front": "die Geschwister", "back": "siblings" },
  { "front": "der Bruder", "back": "brother" },
  { "front": "die Schwester", "back": "sister" },
  { "front": "der Großvater / Opa", "back": "grandfather" },
  { "front": "die Großmutter / Oma", "back": "grandmother" },
  { "front": "die Großeltern", "back": "grandparents" },
  { "front": "der Enkel", "back": "grandson" },
  { "front": "die Enkelin", "back": "granddaughter" },
  { "front": "der Onkel", "back": "uncle" },
  { "front": "die Tante", "back": "aunt" },
  { "front": "der Neffe", "back": "nephew" },
  { "front": "die Nichte", "back": "niece" },
  { "front": "der Cousin", "back": "cousin (male)" },
  { "front": "die Cousine", "back": "cousin (female)" },
  { "front": "die Schwiegermutter", "back": "mother-in-law" },
  { "front": "der Schwiegervater", "back": "father-in-law" },
  { "front": "die Schwiegertochter", "back": "daughter-in-law" },
  { "front": "der Schwiegersohn", "back": "son-in-law" },
  { "front": "der Ehemann", "back": "husband" },
  { "front": "die Ehefrau", "back": "wife" },
  { "front": "die Familie", "back": "family" },
  { "front": "die Kinder", "back": "children" },
  { "front": "der Partner", "back": "partner (male)" },
  { "front": "die Partnerin", "back": "partner (female)" },
  { "front": "das Enkelkind", "back": "grandchild" }
]